(+84) 941 845 497

www.linkedin.com/in/danthi0512

ABOUT ME

"A highly organized, self – motivated, result – oriented, hard – working individual with a willing-to-learn attitude who takes every chance to enhance knowledge, skills and mindset to become Supply Chain Specialist in the short run and Supply Chain Consultant in the long run"

EDUCATION

Foreign Trade University HCMC Campus

Aug 2019 – Aug 2023

- Major: Business International Economics
- Bachelor program
- GPA: 3.62/4.0

Vietnam Logistics and Aviation School

• Course: Supply Chain Executive

Sep 2021 - Nov 2021

Course objectives: Overview of 4 main departments in Supply Chain, Practical experiences and directly interaction on the supply chain management system, Understand Supply Chain structure

WORKING EXPERIENCE

Nestlé Vietnam is a part of Nestle – the world leading food, beverage, health & wellness company **Transportation Intern**

Apr 2022 – Oct 2022

- Work for transport digitization & improvement project:
 - Implement new truck planning process for North with SAP TM system and ensuring no business disruptions during the project transition.
 - Engage in planning and data analysis part of Vehicle Capacity Utilization (VCU) improvement project: Multi-drop points delivery.
 - Achievement: Proactively & effectively working with CS team optimizing sales order to improve delivery VCU from 77% to 82%.
- Transport Management: Booking, tracking and collating transportation service providers and costs related to domestic shipping and containers, truck capacity planning for peak season.
- Other tasks assigned

Wipro Consumer Care Vietnam - leading international FMCG company specialized in premium and high - quality consumer care products

Purchasing Intern Dec 2021 - Mar 2022

- Main in charge for buying overseas packaging material:
 - > Prepare of Purchase Orders on SAP system based on approved requisitions and selected suppliers
 - Manage supplier performance to ensure in full and on-time delivery
 - ldentify and resolve supplier performance issues
 - Arrange booking with freight forwarder for vendor with FOB term
 - Coordinate with Planning and Warehouse team to arrange goods arrival information
- Other projects as assigned & Ad-hoc requests from team lead.

EXTRA - CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Logistics Studying Club – www.lscftu2.com – leading organization in Logistics & Supply Chain Management for university students with the main aim is to help member to enhance both LSCM knowledge and soft skills for future

Jul 2021 – Jun 2022 **President**

- Planning, delegating, organizing, monitoring and evaluating resources, activities and events.
- Directing internal and external relationships

• Improving Club's activities and members' belonging by allocating members to the projects suitable with their capacity and introducing new activities based on Maslow's hierarchy of need.

Learning points: Adaptability, Strategic Thinking, Critical Thinking, Observation

Member of Human Resources and Events Department

Oct 2019 – June 2021

- Planned and executed (Search for suppliers, negotiate & compare vendors, establish suppliers criteria and database, maintain supplier list and commodity buying list,...) for the content of internal and external events
- Allocated, controlled and prepared logistical commodities for the external events
- Successful projects and achievements:
 - Seminar "Tôi nói gì khi nói về Xuất nhập khẩu" number of participants increased by 50%
 - > SCMission Contest 2021: 500+ contestants number of participants increased by 100%
 - Made a deal with 50% discount from venue vendor for SCMission Contest 2021

Learning points: Teamwork, Communication, Stakeholder Management

SKILLS & CERTIFICATES

- Computer literacy: Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Power BI), ERP SAP
- Certificate: Supply Chain Management Specialization | Coursera.org, Procurement Executive | VILAS, KPMG Data Analytics Consulting Virtual Internship | Forage, The Fresh Connection | Inchainge

ACHIEVEMENTS

• Top 8 Supply Chain Management Function at Doanh Nhan Tap Su 2022

June 2022

- ➤ Doanh Nhan Tap Su 2022 is a Vietnamese national student competition simulating the management trainee recruitment process of large companies and corporations hosted by Action Club Foreign Trade University HCMC Campus with 2700+ contestants.
- Top 15 at Mondelez International's Taste the Future SEA Business Challenge

May 2022

- Taste The Future Business Challenge is a virtual competition across South East Asia where contestants will have an opportunity to learn Design Thinking and solve "wicked" business challenges in small teams.
- Our team had surpassed Stage 1: Empathy & Define which build the profile of the end-user and define opportunity to solve to develop business

• Top 20 at Vietnam Supply Chain Challenge

Apr 2022

- > Applying supply chain knowledge into The Fresh Connection simulation game
- Making decisions as an Operation VP while working with Supply Chain VP, Purchasing VP and Sales VP with the highest ROI is 43,35%

• Top 15 at RMIT Business Analyst Champion

Nov 2021

- Using Excel to analyze data relating financial performance and define problems of supply chain operation of a FMCG company
- Making recommendation for company to enhance financial ratios and supply chain

• Top 25 at LogiChain Contest

Aug 2021

- Organized by Logistics & Supply Chain Club of NEU with 120+ teams across Vietnamese Universities
- Proposed solutions for a technology company to improve forecast accuracy and responsiveness, mitigate supply disruption risk due to chip shortage and decrease manufacturing cost by applying Leantools.

REFERENCE

Tran Hong Phat (Mr.)

Transportation Manager – Nestlé Vietnam

Phone: (+84) 939 724 519